Guide to the Stephanie Strickland Papers, 1955-2016 RL.01262
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1970s-2010s
  - Journals and Publications
    - Sarah Lawrence, Fall-Winter 1987-1988 (Box 6)
    - Samizdat 1 and 2, 1998-1999 (Box 6)
    - Black Clock 6, 2006 (Box 6)
    - P-Queue issue (Box 5)
    - The Best American Poetry, 2013 (Box 11)
    - American Poets 46, 2014 (Box 11)
    - Writing & Pedagogy, 2012 (Box 11)
    - Journal of Narrative Theory 43.3, 2013 (Box 11)
    - American Letters & Commentary 12, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Events and Publicity, 1980s-2012
      Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use these records.
      - The Kitchen Reading, 2011 (Box 12)
      - Electronic Reading Exhibit, MLA 2012 (Box 12)
      - Poster: Reading with Judd Morrissey, Chicago Review & New Media Workshop (Box 12)
      - Electronic Literature Organization Conference, 2012 (Box 12)
      - Program for Bridges, 2012 (Box 12)
      - & Now Program, 2011 (Box 12)
      - Simone Weil: Dream of Grace in the Gravity of Contemporary Society, 2012 (Box 12)
      - Interrupt Program, 2012 (Box 12)
      - Grand Valley Writers Series, 2011 (Box 12)
      - Electronic Literature Collection v.2 (Box 12)
      - TP21CL pieces, 1999 (Box 12)
      - Digital Arts and Culture, 2000-2001 (Box 12)
      - Society for Literature and Science, 2003-2004 (Box 12)
      - &Now, 2009 (Box 12)
      - ePoetry, Barcelona, 2009 (Box 12)
      - Writing from the Workplace, 1995 (Box 12)
      - Text One Zero, 2001 (Box 12)
      - Reviews and publicity, 2002-2009 (Box 12)
      - Events and organization handouts, 2000-2011 (Box 12)
      - Event programs, 2009-2012 (Box 12)
      - Visionary Landscapes participants, 2008 (Box 12)
      - Various book reviews (Box 12)
      - Programs, articles, brochures, leaflets, 1980s-1990s (Box 12)
      - Awards and ceremony programs, 1990s-2001 (Box 12)
      - Multimedia Boot Camp (Box 12)
      - Convergence Conference, 1994 (Box 12)
      - ISAMA proceedings, 2009 (Box 12)
      - Proceedings of the CyberMountain Colloquium (Box 5)
      - CyberMountain images, 1999-2000; 10 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL01262-SET-0001)
        Image files in BMP format.
      - ELO 2012 (Box 11)
      - Social Media History and Poetics, 2013 (Box 11)
      - Diasporic Literary Archives - Yale, 2014 (Box 11)
      - Electronic Literature Organization Conference, 2014 (Box 11)
      - SLSA Art Exhibition, 2013 (Box 11)
      - Bridges Conferences Poetry Anthology, 2013 (Box 11)
      - SLSA, 2012 (Box 11)
      - Conference and Event Memorabilia (Box 11)
      - Event Posters (Box 8)
      - Oversize Event Posters (Oversize-folder 1)
      - Hypermedia at the Hammer Museum, 1998-2002, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 57 megabytes; 950 files.
        Materials related to a exhibit including Strickland's work alongside works of several other electronic literature authors. Exhibit materials include web-based files introducing the authors and their work, as well as several works themselves. Files will render in modern web borwsers.
        Works include Strickland and M.D. Coverley's "Errand Upon Which We Came," Stuart Mouthrop's "Penfield Three," Caitlin Fisher's "These Waves of Girls", M.D. Coverley's "Pyxis Byzantium", and Judy Malloy's "Dorothy Abrona McCrae."
      - Progressive Dinner Party, 1999-2000; Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 1 megabyte.
        Web files related to the online exhibit edited by Marjorie Luesebrink titled "Progressive Dinner Party: A tour to the works of women who write hypertext and hypermedia literature on the World Wide Web." Most web files run in contemporary web browsers.
      - Jumpin' at the Diner, 1999-2000; Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 1 megabyte.
        Web files related to "Jumpin' at the Diner," a follow-up to "Progressive Dinner Party" and featuring the work of forty male writers of hypertext and hypermedia literature. Most web files run on contemporary web browsers.
      - ELO Showcase, 2006; Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 22 megabytes.
        Contains web files related to the updating of the Electronic Literature Organization's online showcase of electronic literary work.
      - Stephanie Strickland Website Materials
        - Strickland Website materials, 2001-2003; Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive and external hard drive. Approximately 3 megabytes.
          Includes digital files related to two versions of Strickland's personal website.
        - Strickland Web Archives, 2011-
    - Conference Program ELO, 2015 (Box 16)
      Archiving Roundtable + "House of Trust"
    - Counter-Text, August 2016 (Box 16)
      Interview with Strickland. Volume 2, Issue 2.
    - jai-alai magazine (Box 16)
      "Fourth Fate - Spin Steer". Issue 3.
    - Bone Bouquet, Spring 2016 (Box 16)
      "Fourth Fates - Spin-Stir". Volume 7.
    - Handsome (Box 16)
      "Four Fates - Lot-Fling". Volume 8, no.1.
    - Union, 2015 (Box 16)
      "WaveSon. Net 19-22"
    - Vlak 5, 2015 (Box 16)
      "Song of Buck-Stop"
    - ENTER+, 2014-2015 (Box 17)
      "Repurposing in Sea and Spar Between"
    - Poesia Digital, 2015 (Box 17)
    - Horace Greely High School 50 Years Later, October 2009 (Box 17)
    - Summer Institute in Women's History, 1979 (Box 17)
      Basic Books in the History of American Women
  - Essays, Speeches, Presentations
    - Hypertext for Poets essays, etc., 1995 (Box 14)
    - Poetry in Transition: The Electronic Word essays, etc., 1995 (Box 14)
    - Women's Biography Seminar, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Moving Through Me as I Move version of talk, 2001-2002 (Box 14)
    - Moving Through Me as I Move digital materials, 1999-2002, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 10 megabytes.
      Includes drafts of text for the presentation, as well as the presentation web files. Presentation files are compatible with contemporary web browsers.
    - Making the Vniverse, 2003 (Box 14)
    - People's Poetry Panel talks, April 2003 (Box 14)
    - Writing the Hungry Body: The Red Virgin paper, April 1997 (Box 14)
    - Association of Writing Programs digital materials, 1999-2005; 49 digital files; approximately 65 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL01262-SET-0001)
      Image files (JPEG and BMP formats), multimedia files (HTML, Macromedia, and related formats), and document files (MS Word format).
    - Association for Computing in the Humanities digital materials, 2003-2004, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 100 kilobytes.
    - Beyond Hypertext at Beyond Baroque digital materials, 2002, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 67 megabytes.
    - Digital Arts and Culture digital materials, 1999-2001, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 800 kilobytes.
    - Hypertext 98 digital materials, 1998-1999, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 200 kilobytes.
    - Media Ecology Association digital materials, 2004, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 17 megabytes.
    - Modern Language Association digital materials, 1998-2004, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 190 megabytes.
    - Society for Literature, Science, and the Arts digital materials, 1995-2009, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 155 megabytes.
    - Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division presentation digital materials, 2002-2004, Digital files extracted from USB thumb drive. Approximately 61 megabytes.
    - Guest post on True North and StorySpace, Digital file extracted from USB thumb drive.
  - Writings by Others
    - Suzanne Shimek dissertation, 2001 (Box 14)
      In Uncertain Terms: Poetry, Physics, and Representation in the Quantum Era (UCLA)
    - Edwin Barlow (high school calculus teacher) article by Madeline Rivlin, 2009 (Box 14)
    - Adrienne Dodt thesis on Strickland, 2009 (Box 14)
      Of Specific Paper: Translucence and Synapses (Naropa University)
    - Raine Koskimaa thesis, 2000 (Box 14)
      Digital Literature: From Text to Hypertext and Beyond
    - Denise Larsen thesis, 1986 (Box 14)
      Nansense You Snorsted!: A Romp Through Nonsense
    - Catalog Codings, 2012 (Box 14)
    - Papers written by Marjorie Luesebrink (Box 14)
    - Razor Smile 2, 2003 (Box 14)
    - Hypertext and the Female Imaginary by Jaishree K. Odin, 2010 (Box 14)
    - Materia Sztuki edited by Michal Ostrowicki, 2010 (Box 14)
    - Nick Montfort and Scott Rettberg, Implementation project (Box 14)
    - Cognitive Fictions by Joseph Tabbi, 2002 (Box 6)
    - 1 Rubix cube poem by a student (Box 10)
    - Liberatura, e-literatura i ... Remiksy, remediacje, redefinicje, 2012 (Box 11)
    - The Contemporary Narrative Poem: Critical Crosscurrents, 2012 (Box 11)
    - architectures of possibility after innovative writing, 2012 (Box 11)
    - West Branch 41, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Radcliffe, 1995 (Box 11)
    - The Blurred, Visionary Promise of Hybridized Poetics by Arielle Greenberg, 2012 (Box 11)
    - The Writer's Chronicle, 2013 (Box 11)
    - Glide: An Interactive Exploration of Visual Language by Diana Reed Slattery, Bill Brubaker, and Daniel O'Neill digital files, 2001-2003; Disk images derived from two optical discs. Approximately 125 megabytes.
      Digital files comprise a working version of Glide dated November 2001, which includes executables for the Lexicon, Collabyrinth, and Oracle (beta) components. Digital files also include an additional executable for Glide's Glyph Tunnel dated 2003. All executables require a Windows platform.
    - Erasmaganza by Chris Crawford, Disk image derived from optical disc. Approxmiately 60 megabytes; 1300 files.
      Digital files include an interactive fiction player and a sample fictional piece to demonstrate the application's features. Files compatible with Windows and potentially Macintosh platforms.
    - Califia, Author's Pre-Edition Version by M.D. Coverley, Disk image derived from optical disc. Approximately 367 megabytes.
      Digital files comprise a beta, author's pre-edition of the work from Eastgate Systems. Compatible with 32-bit Windows systems.
    - Various works by Camille Utterback, 1999-2003; Disk images derived from two optical discs. Approximately 1.5 gigabytes.
      Digital files include still images and video of several Utterback installations, including Untitled 5, Potent Objects, External Measures (2001), External Measures (2003), Liquid Time, see/saw, Text Rain, Arc Tangent, Crossing, Come to Pieces, Drawing from Life, and Luminous Fix.
    - Various works by Alan Sondheim, Disk image derived from optical disc. Approximately 4.7 gigabytes.
      Digital files include text, still image, audio, and moving images of the selected works by Sondheim. Appears to be a subset of the works featured on Sondheim's website.
    - Various works by Karen Ackoff, Disk image derived from optical disc. Approximately 41 megabytes.
      Digital files include a sample from the portfolio of Karen Ackoff. Original media meant to run on a Macintosh platform, and documentation suggests a machine running Apple System 7.
    - Cyborg engineering the body electric by Diane Greco, 1995; Disk image derived from floppy disk. (Box 20)
    - The eastgate quarterly review of hypertext, Vol.2, number 1, 1995; Disk images derived from three floppy disks. (Box 20)
    - Electronic literature collection, Vol. 1, 2006 October; Disk image derived from optical disk. (Box 20)
    - The little magazine, Vol. 21, 1995; Disk image derived from optical disk. (Box 20)
    - My name is captain, captain by Judd Morrissey and Lori Talley, 2002; Disk image derived from optical disk. (Box 20)
    - Patchwork girl by Shelley Jackson, 1995; Disk image drived from floppy disk. (Box 20)
    - The unknown: an anthology, 2002; Disk image derived from optical disk. (Box 20)
    - Winchester's nightmare by Nick Montfort, 1999; Disk images created from two floppy disks. (Box 20)
    - 2001 Electronic Literature Awards, 1003 Megabytes
      Digital files related the Electronic Literature Organization's 2001 Electronic Literature Awards. Includes digital files related to the awards program itself--the works in many cases, or essays about the works if compatibility issues barred their inclusion--for both the fiction and poetry award winners and finalists, as well as comments from the judges. Also present are several official entry copies of electronic literary works. The individual entry copies will run only on Macintosh platforms, although the files related to the awards program can be run on multiple computing platforms.
      - 2001 Electronic Literature Awards disc
      - Nepabunna by Geniwate
      - Exhale by Orig Kruglanski and Raquel Paricio
      - Opscula by Elin Sjursen
      - Windsound by John Cayley
      - Cyberpoetry Underground by Komninos Zervos
      - My Name is Captain, Captain by Judd Morrisey
    - Notes on Statistical Mechanics, 1965 (Box 17)
      Acknowledgement for Mrs. Stephanie Pfaff (her in the past)
  - Volume of calligraphy of Strickland poems by Kevin Honan, circa 1990s (Box 8)
- Education and Academia, 1950s-2000s
  - Grade School work, 1950s (Box 6)
  - High School papers, 1950s-1960s (Box 6)
  - College notes, 1960s (Box 6)
  - College papers, Harvard, 1959-1963; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Graduate work - LIS, Pratt (Box 6)
  - Programs, posters, letters, announcements, photos (Box 6)
  - Strickland's resume/CV, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Diplomas (Box 6)
  - New Media and Literature syllabus and materials (Box 6)
  - Marble Springs, by Deena Larson (teaching materials, correspondence, text) (Box 6)
  - Cyberpoets Guide to Virtual Culture, by John Frost (Box 6)
  - Internet Poetry Sources notebook, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Publisher materials (Box 6)
  - Hyperpoetry articles by Stephanie Strickland and others (Box 6)
  - Harvard diploma (Box 8)
  - Program/exhibit posters (Box 8)
  - Howard Foundation Application: Print, also disk (Box 5, Box 6)
- Miscellany, 1950s-2016
  - Ephemera (Box 5)
  - Mementoes, undated (Box 5)
  - Artwork: Stand Under, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Gallery catalogs that influenced Strickland's work, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
  - YLEM, 1998-2007 (not a complete set) (Box 5)
  - Assorted miscellany, including some early e-conferences programs and ISAMA 2009 program (Box 4)
  - Book covers (Box 10)
  - Eastgate Systems guides (Box 10)
  - Personal Documents, 1957-2007 (Box 11)
  - Life Celebrations, 2012-2013 (Box 11)
    Memorial programs for Rose Anne Burstein, who hired Strickland at the Sarah Lawrence Library, Paul Ryan, a collaborator on slippingglimpse, and Rebecca Harding Davis, a relative of Strickland's friend, Rachel Loden, who attended the same seminary Strickland's grandmother did (Washington Seminary, 1906).
  - Miscellaneous editing jobs, 2002-2006, 8 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL01262-SET-0001)
    Document files in MS Word format.
  - GraphicArchive still images, 1997-2000; 85 files; approximately 15 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL01262-SET-0001)
    Image files in BMP and GIF formats, HTML web files, and a single audio file in MIDI format.
  - Reading Poster, 2011 (Box 17)
  - Feminist Poetics and the Internet, 2015 (Box 17)
  - &NOW Feminist Panel discussion, 2015 (Box 17)
  - Ahsanta Press 40th Anniversary Reading Poster, 2014 (Box 17)
  - The Kitchen, 2016 Sept. 10 (Box 17)
- Audiovisual, 1983-2002; 1
  - Eduardo Kac: Holopoetry 1983-1990; New Holopoems 1993, 1983-1993; 1
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0005)
  - Interviews with Authors: Guest: Stephanie Strickland, 1992 March 25; 2
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0002)
    - Original DVD (Box 7, Video-disc RL-01262-dvd-0001)
  - S. Strickland on Weil 12/93 WORT 89.9 FM Madison, WI 1) Labor 2) Women, 1992 December; 3
    - Original audiocassette (Box 7, Audio-cassette RL-01262-cs-0002)
  - Small Press - Strickland / English, 1993 May 11; 4
    - Original audiocassette (Box 7, Audio-cassette RL-01262-cs-0003)
  - Jean Feraca: The Life of Simone Weil: Stephanie Strickland, 1993 August 25; 5
    - Original audiocassette (Box 7, Audio-cassette RL-01262-cs-0004)
  - "To the Best of Our Knowledge," segment on Simone Weil, 1993 August 25; 6
    - Original compact disc (Box 7, Audio-disc RL-01262-cd-0001)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 7, Audio-cassette RL-01262-cs-0005)
    - Original compact disc (Box 7, Audio-disc RL-01262-cd-0002)
  - Denise Duhamel and Stephanie Strickland: Poetry Reading 10/22/97 Gerry LaFemina, 1997 October 22; 7
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0003)
    - Original DVD (Box 7, Video-disc RL-01262-dvd-0001)
  - Euclid 1999 / Slow.Time 1999 / Knoebel ~5:00, 8
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0001)
  - Sisyphus by HO, 1999; 9
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0004)
  - Technopoetry Festival 2002 Symposium #1, 10
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0006)
  - Technopoetry Festival 2002 Symposium #2, 11
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0007)
  - Technopoetry Festival 2002 Symposium #3, 12
    - Original VHS videocassette (Box 7, Video-cassette RL-01262-vhs-0008)
  - WNYE/FM Small Press Cntr "Strickland", undated; 13
    - Original audiocassette (Box 7, Audio-cassette RL-01262-cs-0001)
- Unprocessed Additions
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access restricted; collection requires additional arrangement, description, and/or screening. Contact research services for more information.
  - Acc. 2020/0043 (Box 2020/0043: Box 1, Box 2020/0043: Box 2)
    Books and journals containing Strickland's work. Drafts, information about conferences and events.
  - Acc. 2020/0067, 1976-2010 (Box 2020/0067: Box 1, Box 2020/0067: Box 2, Box 2020/0067: Box 3, Box 2020/0067: Box 4, Box 2020/0067: Box 5)
    Drafts, journals, notebooks, anthologies and other papers of electronic literature.